Guide to the Frederieke S. Taylor Papers MSS.570
Fales Library and Special Collections
Frederieke S. Taylor Papers
1966-2019
1990s-2010s
Fales Library and Special Collections
Taylor, Frederieke S.
Halvorson-Taylor, Martien A.
Taylor, D. Severn
MSS.570
13.65 Linear Feet in 22 manuscript boxes, 2 media boxes, and 2 small card boxes.
79.16 Gigabytes in 26,119 computer files.
8 videocassettes (vhs)
2 videocassettes (dvcam)
1 websites in one archived website.
Frederieke Taylor (1940-2018) was an art collector, curator, and New York City gallery owner. The Frederieke S. Taylor Papers primarily document the management of the Frederieke Taylor Gallery through paper and electronic files on artists, exhibitions, and administrative files. A significant portion of the paper collection is the gallery's artist information files dating from 1990 to 2010. This collection also includes chronological gallery exhibition material; administrative files; business contact cards; and appointment calendars from the 1970s to the mid-2010s. A small amount of material related to Taylor's early exhibition curating in the 1970s and images from her own personal art collection can also be found in this collection.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Martien Halvorson-Taylor and D. Severn Taylor, October 2018. The accession number associated with this gift is 2019.013.
https://frederieketaylor.com/ was added to the web archive in April 2019. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. THe accession number associated with this website is 2019.064.
Appraisal
13 discs were removed from the collection either because they were damaged or, after forensic imaging and analysis, determined to contained duplicate data. These discs were returned to the donor, 10/23/2019.
Arrangement
Artists' files are arranged alphabetically by last name. File entries are listed by ranges of artists' last name within each box. The remaining files in the collection are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical Note
Frederieke Taylor (1940-2018) was an art collector, curator, and administrator who exhibited contemporary art at the gallery she co-founded in SoHo in 1993. In the 1960s, she immigrated from the Netherlands. Taylor worked as director for the MacDowell Colony in New Hampshire and directed the Skowhegan School for Painting and Sculpture. Taylor also curated and organized exhibitions, and coordinated "Deconstructivist Architecture" at the Museum of Modern Art in 1988. In 1993, Taylor opened TZ'Art, a gallery in SoHo, with a partner, Tom Zollner. After five years, Taylor took over sole ownership and renamed it the Frederieke Taylor Gallery. The artists, sculptors, and architects exhibited at the gallery include Lisa Sigal, Thomas Zummer, Mel Chin, Raimund Abraham, Long-Bin Chen and Meredith Monk.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Fales Library and Special Collections with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains paper and digital files, an archived website, and audiovisual recordings related to the Frederieke Taylor Gallery. The gallery represented artists, sculptors, and architects, including Lisa Sigal, Thomas Zummer, Mel Chin, Raimund Abraham, Long-Bin Chen, and Meredith Monk. A significant portion of the paper files in this collection contain artist material assembled by the gallery for those artists they represented. These binders date from the 1980s to mid-2010s and typically contain an artist's resume and statement; press clippings; and paper and digital images of their artwork. Similar artist material can also be found within the gallery's digital administrative files which contain gallery emails; client lists; art fair files; advertising; and content for the gallery's online blog. The small number of audiovisual materials within this collection were either provided by the artist to promote their work, or were used as part of a gallery exhibition. The gallery also assembled binders containing material from their exhibitions, dating from 1993 to 2010 which includes lists of artworks, promotional material, catalogs, and press clippings. Gallery administrative material includes paper and digital files containing promotional material; exhibition catalogs; notebooks containing daily tasks and artist studio visit notes; images of the gallery space; exhibition guest books; business contact cards; and appointment calendars dating from 1974 to 2015. Files on Taylor's curatorial work in the late 1970s while working with the Institute of Architecture and Urban Studies are in this collection. This collection also contains digital images and supporting documentation for Taylor's personal art collection.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Slides (photographs); Brochures.; Appointment books.; Correspondence.; Artists. -- New York (State) -- New York. -- 20th century; Art galleries, Commerical -- New York (State) -- New York; Art -- Exhibitions -- New York (State) -- New York.; SoHo (New York, N.Y.); Halvorson-Taylor, Martien A.; Taylor, D. Severn; Frederieke Taylor Gallery; Frederieke Taylor/Tz'art Gallery; Abraham, Raimund, 1933-2010; Chen, Long-Bin, 1964-; Chin, Mel, 1951-; Monk, Meredith; Sigal, Lisa; Zummer, Thomas
- Archived Website, April 2019; 1 websites in one archived website. (E-records Electronic Records)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of frederieketaylor.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Scope and Contents
  The website of the Frederieke Taylor Gallery contains a history of the gallery and its former locations and names, as well as an exhibition history dating from 2000-2017, and artist webpages containing resumes, exhibitions, and images of selected works. Artists featured on the website include Antenna Design, Bejamin Britton, Barbara Broughel, Breaded Escalope, Long-Bin Chen, Mel Chin, [dNASAb], Jackie Ferrara, Peter Hutchinson, Raquel Maulwurf, Franco Mondini-Ruiz, Meredith Monk, Kristen Nelson, Christy Rupp, Christian Wassmann, Pauline Wiertz, Marion Wilson, and Thomas Zummer.
- Artists: Raimund Abraham -- Barbara Broughel, 1991-2013; cuid30338 (Box 1, Folder 1-6, E-records Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_570_ER_1)
- Artists: Mary Ellen Carroll -- Winka Dubbledam, 1998-2017; cuid30339 (Box 2, Folder 1-6, E-records Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_570_ER_2)
- Artists: Winka Dubbeldam -- Julie Langsam, 1970-2017; cuid30340 (Box 3, Folder 1-7, E-records Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_570_ER_3)
- Artists: Mary Lum -- Franco Mondini-Ruiz, 1991-2015; cuid30341 (Box 4, Folder 1-6, E-records Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_570_ER_4)
- Artists: Meredith Monk -- Christy Rupp, 1966, 1981-2010; cuid30342 (Box 5, Folder 1-6, E-records Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_570_ER_5)
- Artists: Christy Rupp -- Ellen Zweig, 1981-2015; cuid30343 (Box 6, Folder 1-7, E-records Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_570_ER_6)
- Artists: Thomas Zummer, 2002-2008 (Box 6, Folder 8, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Artist and Exhibition Binder Material: Breaded Escalope and In the Viewing Room, 1981-2017 (Box 7, Folder 2-5)
- Artists' Audiovisual Material, 1966, 1996-2002 (Box 24)
- Exhibitions, 1993-1998 (Box 7, Folder 6, Box 8, Folder 1-3)
- Exhibitions, 1999-2002 (Box 8, Folder 4-5, Box 9, Folder 1-2)
- Exhibitions, 2002-2003 (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
- Exhibitions, 2006-2010 (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
- Administrative Files, 1978-2017; cuid30337 (Box 11, Folder 1-7, Box 12, Box 13, Box 14, Folder 1-8, Box 15, Folder 1-5, Box 21, Folder 2-3, E-records Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_570_ER_7)
- Appointment Books, 1975-1979 (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
- Appointment Books, 1980-1989 (Box 17, Folder 1-4)
- Appointment Books, 1990-2000 (Box 18, Folder 1-3, Box 19, Folder 1-2)
- Appointment Books, 2001-2015 (Box 19, Folder 3-4, Box 20, Folder 1-3, Box 21, Folder 1)
- Rolodex and Business Contact Notecards, undated (Box 22, Box 23)
- Frederieke Taylor Art Collection, 2004-2013; cuid30344 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_570_ER_8)
- Gallery Files Backup, 1996-2018; cuid30345 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_570_ER_9)